<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Blog on</title><link>https://foreops.com/blog/</link><description>Recent content in Blog on</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-US</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 06 Oct 2020 08:49:55 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://foreops.com/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Container Scanning with Trivy in Jenkins</title><link>https://foreops.com/blog/trivy-intro/</link><pubDate>Fri, 02 Jul 2021 11:00:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://foreops.com/blog/trivy-intro/</guid><description>You can identify and address the security vulnerabilities earlier in the software development life-cycle if you integrate a scanner in the continuous integration (CI) pipelines. There are multiple open-source and commercial tools out there that can scan the applications and containers. When comparing these tools, we consider the following aspects:
Easier integration with the pipelines through plugins, scripts, or API calls. Faster, ideally synchronous execution. It should not hold up the build pipeline.</description></item><item><title>Introduction to Terraform</title><link>https://foreops.com/blog/terraform-intro/</link><pubDate>Fri, 02 Jul 2021 11:00:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://foreops.com/blog/terraform-intro/</guid><description>Cloud vendors provide their own scripting languages for infrastructure management, such as AWS&amp;rsquo;s Cloud Formation or Azure&amp;rsquo;s Resource Manager Templates, but scripting with those can easily get complicated, brittle, and hard to maintain. Terraform uses the simple yet powerful HashiCorp Configuration Language (HCL) which can be scaled easily to an entire enterprise without the side-effects. Terraform has been embraced across the industry and has also been gaining favor with major cloud providers.</description></item><item><title>Admission Control in Kubernetes</title><link>https://foreops.com/blog/kubernetes-admission-control/</link><pubDate>Mon, 28 Jun 2021 11:00:16 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://foreops.com/blog/kubernetes-admission-control/</guid><description>They come in handy to implement or validate resource limits or ensure that the deployments are not using the &amp;ldquo;latest&amp;rdquo; image tags. For instance, you can restrict pods to pull container images from certain registries or disallow containers to run in privileged mode. In addition, admission controllers can enforce label naming conventions or add annotations, such as a cost center to objects.
The admission controllers intercept requests made to the API server before the persistence of the object.</description></item><item><title>Kubernetes Authorization</title><link>https://foreops.com/blog/kubernetes-authorization/</link><pubDate>Fri, 11 Jun 2021 21:31:44 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://foreops.com/blog/kubernetes-authorization/</guid><description>Kubernetes API Server is implemented as a RESTful API service and acts as a front end to its control plane. REST is an architecture style developed by Roy Thomas Fielding. One of the guiding principles of REST is statelessness. Each request from a client must contain all the information required to complete the request, including authentication and authorization. The RESTful API implementation in Kubernetes makes it compatible with existing on-prem or cloud access systems.</description></item><item><title>Kubernetes Authentication</title><link>https://foreops.com/blog/kubernetes-authentication/</link><pubDate>Fri, 04 Jun 2021 13:12:08 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://foreops.com/blog/kubernetes-authentication/</guid><description>This post will discuss authentication methods for two types of accounts that access the Kubernetes cluster: users and machines. While cluster administrators and application developers require access to the cluster to manage and deploy applications respectively, machines, processes, and applications also need access to the cluster, which they obtain through the service accounts.
Kubernetes Authentication User Authentication Kubernetes does not have objects which represent user accounts. Users do not log in, and there are no sessions or timeouts.</description></item></channel></rss>